Okay, so in this section we're going to talk about noise versus signal.
好的 在这部分 我们将讨论信号与噪音
Now job is to look for correlation and neural nets can do very,
神经网络的任务 就是寻找相关性
very good at that.
而神经网络可以做得非常好
However, once again, this talks about framing the problem so
不过现在 我们又得谈到如何设计问题
that the neural nets have the most advantage and can train and
让神经网络能发挥最大优势 可以训练
understand the most complicated patterns of these as possible.
并理解最复杂的模式
And so what we saw on our last section is that wow this thing
上一节 我们看到的是
really wasn't training very quickly.
它的确训练速度不怎么快
It seemed like there's a lot more signal in this, excellent, versus terrible,
似乎 有些地方信号更多 比如 excellent 与 terrible 相对
versus moving, versus, you know,
moving 对其他什么词
what we can some of these other words that are really positive or negative.
可以看到 有些词是非常正面或负面的
It just seems like if I as a human was looking at this text I could predict
似乎作为人类 我只看到这些文本
better than 60% accuracy using just the words.
只用这些词汇 预测准确率就能达到 60% 以上
So what we want to do is go back to, but
我们现在要做的是回到……
before we start getting fancy with crazy regularization or
先不做一些花里胡哨的、高级的正则化
fancy things in the neural net we want to go back to the data.
而是先回到数据本身
The data is where all of the gold is.
数据是金子所在的地方
Like the neural net is just the backhoe that we're going to
而神经网络就像是一台挖掘机 我们用它
dig all the gold out of the ground with.
来将所有的金子挖出来
But if we're not finding much gold, especially in the beginning,
但如果我们挖不到太多金子 尤其是在一开始
it's probably not a problem with our backhoe.
问题很可能不在于挖掘机
It's probably a problem with where we're digging, the dirt that we're choosing,
而在于我们挖掘的位置 选择的地块
how we're manipulating it.
以及操纵它的方式
And so, what I want to talk about here is noise versus signal because that's
那么 我想在这里谈论的是噪音与信号
the whole game.
因为这就是关键所在
The whole game is saying we have a ton of data, we know there's a pattern in
这里指的是 我们有海量的数据 我们知道存在某种模式
here, we want the neural net to be able to find it.
我们希望神经网络可以找到它
Now earlier, by kind of sheer luck, when we created this update_input_layer,
之前 当我们创建这个 update_input_layer 时 完全靠运气
I saw an 18 here.
我在这里看到了 18
And at the time, it kind of checked off my mind.
当时 我有点惊讶
Wow, that's really high.
哇 真的很高
Consider from me what it's like if there was an 18 right here, right?
从我的角度想想 如果这里出现一个 18 会是什么情况？
So what this is, this for propagation, it's a weighted sum so
那么 对于这个正向传播 这是一个加权求和
there's four weights coming out of this input layer, right?
来自输入层的四个权重的加权和 对吧？
One gets multiplied times four, one gets multiplied times these four and
值 1 分别乘以 4 个权值   这个 1 同样乘以 4 个权值
then those two vectors are summed here.
然后这两个向量在这里相加
So it's a weighted sum,
它是一个加权和
well it's actually a weighted sums of weighted sums, but whatever.
它实际上是加权和的加权和 但不管了
This vector is characteristic of horrible.
这个向量就是 horrible 的特征
So when I say vector, I mean the list of weights, so this weight, this weight,
我这里说的向量 是指权值组成的列表 也就是这个权值
and this weight, have a certain impact on these four nodes.
这个权值 这个还有这个 它们对这四个节点施加一定的影响
[LAUGH] You know it's funny, they kind of interpret each other, right?
[笑] 有意思的是 它们两者有点互相影响
So how high this number is affects how dominantly
这个值有多大 就会影响这些权重
these weights control this hidden layer.
对这个隐藏层的控制力有多强
And these weights control how dominantly this input affects this hidden layer.
而这些权重决定了这个输入值对隐藏层的影响力有多大
So they're multiplied by each other and it's an associative thing, so
两者互乘 互相关联
that they both kind of interplay with each other in that way.
以这种方式相互影响
However, if this is multiplied by 18, and
但是 如果这个乘以 18
this is multiplied by 1, this is going to be the dominant.
而这个乘以 1 那么 这个将占主导地位
I mean,
因为
this vector is basically going to be exactly the same as these four weights.
这个向量一定会等于这四个权值
For horrible, multiplied by 18, like is a percentage of the amount of energy
给 horrible 乘以 18 就像是这些节点的能量占比
that's in these nodes it's going to be mostly this word and so
主要将被这个词占据
I was looking at this and was going, okay which one is being weighted by 18?
我当时看到这个 就想 哪个词被 18 加权了？
Well if we look at word index,
如果我们看一下word2index
Sorry, vocab 0, because this is the zeroth position.
抱歉 应该是 vocab[0] 因为这是第零个位置
Or is that review vocab, reviews, is it reviews vocab?
或者是 review.vocab 是 reviews.vocab 吗？
Might have been, I might have deleted it.
我可能把它删了
Get back here.
回到这里
[INAUDIBLE] We'll add.
哦 是list(vocab)
Okay, so this is it.
好的 对了
So it's nothing.
这个词就是 “空格”
[LAUGH] So when I took [INAUDIBLE] one of the words is a nothing word.
[笑] 当我将词汇标记化以后 其中一个词就是一个“空格”而已
And I look in here and I go well there was 18 of them.
再看这儿 居然有 18 个“空格”
One of them is probably fine, and the neural net can sort that out.
如果只有一个 那还好 神经网络还能够自我分辨
But you know it's seeing mostly nothing in this vector, and
但是 这里 向量表示最多的就是毫无信息的“空格”
then word over here, word over here, very softly, right?
但是这些词 这些词 权重都被弱化了 对吧？
You know I look at kind of the rest of things.
我再看看其他的
So let's just review that split [SOUND] space,
比如说 review.split(“ “)
review 0 space space.
应该是 reviews[0].split(“ “)
Okay.
好
Empty, empty, empty.
空格 空格
Look at that, empty, empty.
看看 都是空格
So at first I'm thinking okay, maybe a tokenization error, but
第一点 可能有一些标记化的错误 但是
then there's a whole bunch of periods in here, so period happens a bunch.
这里有一大堆句号 有很多句号
I wonder what the distribution is?
我想知道它的分布是什么
So a single review_counter = counter, right?
那么单个 review_counter = Counter() 对吧？
So for words is reviews(0).split,
所以 for word in reviews[0].split(“ “):
review_counter word equals one.
review_counter[word] += 1
So, once again, using these counters.
所以 再用一次计数器
I love these counters.
我喜欢用计数器
Review counter, most common, show me.
review_counter.most_common() 显示一下
Wow, look at that.
哇塞 看看
Look at that.
快看看
The dominant words, these have nothing to do with sentiment.
使用频率最高的这些词 都与情绪无关
So there's going to be some standard words down here,
下面应该有一些情绪词
but, insightful it's right there.
insightful 在这里
But when you look at this, most
但如果你看看这个
of this review are completely irrelevant filler words like the, to, I, is, of, a.
评论里大部分词都是一些毫无价值的凑数词 像 the、to、I、is、of、a
And this waiting is causing it to have a dominant effect in the hidden layer,
而这种加权 使它对隐藏层产生了主导影响
and the hidden layer is all of the output layer gets to
而隐藏层正是输出层赖以预测的
use to try to make a prediction.
数据来源
So if this hidden layer doesn't have rich information,
如果隐藏层不能提供丰富的信息
the output layer is going to struggle.
输出层就难为无米之炊了
So now I'm sitting here going okay wait, we decided to do counts earlier.
现在我想 我们之前决定一开始就进行计数
Maybe counts was a bad idea, because the counts doesn't highlight the signal.
或许这不是个好主意 因为计值没有突显信号
When I'm looking at these counts it seems like it highlights the noise.
看看这些计数 它们似乎突显的是噪音
But when I say highlight what I mean is weights it most heavily.
我这里说的突显 是指赋予最多的权重
Neural nets they're just weights and functions.
神经网络只是关于一堆权重和函数
Like you take this, these set of values, you re-weight them, right,
例如 你取这些值 赋予新的权重
into these four nodes, and then you run a function.
到这四个节点 然后运行一个函数
In this case we don't do a function here, but it's a linear function.
在这个例子中 我们没有运行函数 但它是线性的
And then we re-weight them again, and we do a function, and
然后再重新加权 运行一个函数
that's our prediction, right?
就得到了预测值 对吧？
So if our weighting is off, or how we're creating our input data,
但是如果加权没有用 通过我们创建的输入数据
it's going to make it really hard to find the signal.
会难以找到真正的信号
That's noise.
这些都是噪音
That means that the way that we're framing the problem is
这意味着 我们对问题的设计本身
adding a significant amount of noise.
添加了大量噪音
Because in these weights, the neural net has to learn to be like, hey,
因为在这些权重中 神经网络要学习的是
period, quiet down.
嘿 句号 安静点
Hey entity, quiet down, v, two, I, high, is, of, a.
嘿 空格 安静一下 the、to、i、high、is、of、a
Quiet down.
都别吱声
I need to hear insightful.
我想听到的是 insightful
I need to hear welcome.
我要听 welcome
I need to hear other positive, because this is positive view.
我想听到其他积极的词汇 因为这是一条正面评论
I don't know if it's a negative review we could look too, but
我们也可以看看负面评论
this neural net is trying to quiet down all the words that aren't relevant and
但是 这个神经网络试图让所有不相关的单词都安静下来
listen more attentively to the words that are relevant.
然后用心倾听那些真正相关的单词
But we're not helping it by causing the weight to be the things that are most
而我们并没有在帮助它 因为让最大的权重赋予了
frequent.
最高频的内容
And so I think that we should try eliminating this.
所以 我觉得我们应该试着消除这一点
So in project four I think we're going to try that.
在项目 4 中 我们会尝试这么做
So let me go ahead and describe what that's going to be.
我先来描述一下我们要做的事情
So we're going to grab
首先 我们将利用
the code that we had for
项目 3 中完成的
Project 3.
代码
So we going to go down to Project 4, and say okay,
然后来到项目 4 也就是
Project 4: Reducing Noise in our Input Data.
项目 4：减少输入数据中的噪音
Right?
对吧？
And we're going to take this network and we're going to say, okay, how can
我们将使用这个网络 然后思考：
we modify this network so that we don't weight it by these counts anymore?
如何修改这个网络 让它不再按出现次数加权呢？
Well, if we don't weigh it by its counts anymore,
如果我们不再按出现次数加权
then that means that this would always be a one or a zero.
这意味着 它的值将总是 1 或 0
So at this point we're changing it so
这样
that it's just a representation to vocabulary in general.
它只是表示是否出现了该词汇
If we did that that should work actually, because then okay, so
如果这样做 应该会有用
the period and the the, and to, and I will still be in here,
这些句号和 the、and、to、I 还会在这里
the neural net has to decided which words are most important.
神经网络需要抉择哪些词最重要
But it doesn't have to say okay, period times 27, so
但它无需再给句号乘以 27
27 times the weights where period going into the hidden layer.
即在句号进入隐藏层时 用 27 乘以权重
That's a lot of signal to push back down, where as if we just say ones and
这会遮盖许多其他信号 而如果我们只用 1 和 0
zeros, and do a binary representation, that should be a lot less noisy and
以二进制方式来表示 就会大大减少噪音
a lot easier for the neuron to figure out.
使神经元更容易做出判断
Now I think in here, that's actually going to be pretty easy to change, and
我觉得 在这里 改起来应该很容易
I'll just do that project right here.
我就在这个项目中操作
So it's in our update_input_layer.
所以 这是我们的 update_input_layer
Before we were incrementing it, if we just get rid of that plus we're going to
我们这里不做累加 而是去掉加号
set it to equal one so to each value in layer zero we're going to set to
将它设为等于 1 所以对于 layer_0 中的每个值
equal one if that vocabulary term exists.
如果该词汇存在 就让它等于 1
Okay so let's rebuild that.
好的 我们重新构建它
And then let's grab our training value from up here.
利用上面的训练值
We'll do our original one.
我们会使用原来那些
And we need our trained one too.
我们也需要训练值
Copy that and get rid of that.
复制这个 删掉那个
So have a record, go down here.
在下面这里记录它
Create our network.
创建我们的网络
And this is our, basically our new class, and hit train.
这实际上是我们新的类 然后点击“训练”
Look at that, look at that.
快看 快看
It's already to 60% after 2% of progress.
2% 的进度后已经达到 60% 准确度了
This is amazing progress, look at that.
真是惊人的进步 快看
So we eliminated a lot of our noise, right, by getting rid of this weighting.
所以我们通过摆脱这种加权 消除了很多噪音
And the neural net was able to find correlation so much faster.
神经网络也很快地找到了相关性
Look at that, 70%.
快看 70%
And we're only 9% into training.
而我们的训练进度才到 9%
See, this is what increasing a signal and reducing the noise is all about.
这就是增加信号和减少噪音的精髓所在
It's about making it more obvious for your neural net so
那就是让信号在你的神经网络显得更明显
that it can get to work at handling the signal and
使神经网络可以工作起来 正确处理信号
then combining it in interesting ways and looking for more difficult patterns.
以有意思的方式来结合信号 寻找更复杂的模式
And you just kind of get rid of the noise in your training data.
而你就可以摆脱训练数据中的噪音
We could have spent days and days and days up here just tweaking our little
我们可以花上几天时间在这里调整我们的
alpha, just moving it around, lowering it down, trying to get the train to
阿尔法 试着调低一点 让训练速度更慢一点
happen slowly but in reality we can have a big fat alpha and make huge steps and
但在现实中 如果我们能摆脱这些讨厌的噪音
progress really quickly if we just get rid of this really silly noise,
就可以快速取得巨大进步
because we're trying to train our neural nets to do interesting stuff.
因为我们在训练神经网络做些有趣的事情
Interesting stuff is not ignore periods.
有趣的事不是指要忽略句号
Interesting stuff is identify which words are relevent.
而是指识别哪些词有相关性
Identify which combinations of words are relevent.
识别哪些词的组合具有相关性
That's what we want our neural net to do.
这是我们想让神经网络做的事情
Finding interesting representations,
发现有意思的表达
doing interesting things in this hidden layer
在隐藏层进行有趣的操作
to really understand the vocabulary of what's being said in the review.
真正理解评论中所用的词汇
That's what we want to be happening.
这是我们希望看到的
Man, look at that, almost 80%.
看 接近 80% 了
So I'll go ahead and let this keep training.
那么 我会让它继续训练
Go ahead and train this yourself, and
你自己也可以大胆地训练试试
yeah, so this is looking great.
看起来还不错
The next thing I'm noticing, I guess maybe just because this is a video.
我注意到的另外一点…… 可能因为这是一个视频
I would like for this to be training a lot faster.
我希望这个能训练得更快一些
So the next thing that I would like for us to be able to do is kind of take
接下来我希望做的是探寻
a look inside the neural net, understanding what's going on,
神经网络内部 理解所发生的一切
and see if we can kind of crank out a little bit more speed.
看我们能不能进一步提高速度
But for now, I'm going to let this go ahead and train.
不过现在 我们就继续讲课 让它继续训练吧